
000
ACUS11 KWNS 100143
SWOMCD
SPC MCD 100143 
GAZ000-ALZ000-MSZ000-100315-

Mesoscale Discussion 0184
NWS Storm Prediction Center Norman OK
0843 PM CDT Mon Mar 09 2026

Areas affected...portions of central and eastern Alabama into
western Georgia

Concerning...Severe Thunderstorm Watch 30...

Valid 100143Z - 100315Z

The severe weather threat for Severe Thunderstorm Watch 30
continues.

SUMMARY...An MCS will continue to move east/southward across AL/GA
this evening with a risk for damaging gusts.

DISCUSSION...As of 0140 UTC, regional radar imagery showed an
initially loosely organized cluster of thunderstorms had developed
into an MCS across portions of AL and western GA. The environment
remains broadly unstable and moderately sheared across much of the
southeast, which should continue to maintain organized bowing
segments and supercells.

While not overly intense, more organization has been noted within
the MCS over the last two hours, suggesting a consolidated cold pool
and stronger surface pressure gradient has developed. This will
support the potential for damaging gusts (max 60-65 mph), and
possibly a QLCS tornado or two as the convective complex continues
east/southeastward into parts of eastern AL and west-central GA
(including the Atlanta Metro in 1-2 hours) this evening.

Additional strong thunderstorms, including a few supercells, will
remain possible on the upshear side of the complex over central AL.
Additional upscale growth appears likely with time. This would favor
damaging gusts and some hail potential with the stronger supercells.
Given the persistent severe threat, WW30 remains in effect until
0300 UTC, but may be locally extended in time and area as convection
continues to move through AL/GA.

..Lyons.. 03/10/2026

...Please see www.spc.noaa.gov for graphic product...

ATTN...WFO...FFC...BMX...MEG...JAN...

LAT...LON   34548528 34338435 33108356 32398385 32198451 32078551
            32398683 32608746 32868798 33158829 33328844 33568842
            33788823 33818743 33838667 33938607 34128578 34548528 

MOST PROBABLE PEAK TORNADO INTENSITY...85-115 MPH
MOST PROBABLE PEAK WIND GUST...55-70 MPH
MOST PROBABLE PEAK HAIL SIZE...1.00-1.75 IN


